<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/static/styles/feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   <title>HSP</title>
   <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//</link>
   <description>Recent content on HSP</description>
   <language>en-IN</language>
   <webMaster>HSP</webMaster>
   <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International.</copyright>
   <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:08:12 +0530</lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FOSS Meetup-June</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/fossmeetupjuly.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/fossmeetupjuly.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#table-of-contents&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#talk-1-building-a-complete-cross-framework&#34;&gt;Talk 1: Building a Complete Cross Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#talk-2-how-has-the-shadow-dom-got-you-covered&#34;&gt;Talk 2: How has the Shadow DOM got you covered?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#talk-3-streamlining-app-quality-with-detox&#34;&gt;Talk 3: Streamlining App Quality with Detox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#panel-discussion-on-cybersecurity&#34;&gt;Panel Discussion on Cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On July 1, 2023, we attended FOSS United Bangalore&#39;s first-ever themed meetup! It was a whole day dedicated to Frontend! It was our first time attending a FOSS meetup and we&#39;re looking forward to attending many more! There were three talks on different areas of Frontend Development and a panel discussion on Cybersecurity which covered various important aspects of the domain with the valuable opinions of industry experts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;talk-1-building-a-complete-cross-framework&#34;&gt;Talk 1: Building a Complete Cross Framework &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#talk-1-building-a-complete-cross-framework&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vaibhavshn&#34;&gt;Vaibhav Shinde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the first talk, an engineer from Dyte showed us how his company built cross-framework UI kits with the help of web components.&#xA;He covered how his company specializes in enhancing live events with all the features you&#39;d need, including audio/video conference, live streaming and chat, all in one SDK.&#xA;He also provided an overview of various frameworks, including Preact and LIT, as well as Stencil and Fast, and a glimpse into essential tools like Snabbdom, Stencil, PostCSS and Autoprefixer which he uses in his work. To finish it off, we were introduced to React Storybook, a valuable tool for building UI components in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;talk-2-how-has-the-shadow-dom-got-you-covered&#34;&gt;Talk 2: How has the Shadow DOM got you covered? &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#talk-2-how-has-the-shadow-dom-got-you-covered&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/mukulramchandani/&#34;&gt;Mukul Ramchandani&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second session was a journey into the world of ShadowDOM. A passionate frontend engineer from Hublio started with an anecdote from his mom &amp;quot;We don&#39;t look at our shadows anymore because we&#39;re too busy looking at our phones&amp;quot;. Yikes!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He explained to us what Shadow DOM is and it&#39;s significance in front-end development. We also learnt about differentiating between light and ShadowDOM and understanding their respective use cases and were given an in-depth look at how ShadowDOM ensures scoped styles and DOM encapsulation.&#xA;He explored the composability and encapsulation aspects of ShadowDOM and showed us an example of an event model within the ShadowDOM context. He also gave us a comparative analysis of the LIT and Polymer frameworks.&#xA;To wrap up the talk we were introduced to &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.dev/shadowdom/&#34;&gt;web.dev/shadowdom&lt;/a&gt; a resource for further exploration into the Shadows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;talk-3-streamlining-app-quality-with-detox&#34;&gt;Talk 3: Streamlining App Quality with Detox &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#talk-3-streamlining-app-quality-with-detox&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Speaker: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/swetatanwar/&#34;&gt;Sweta Tanwar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The final session was a deep dive into end-to-end testing for applications by a mobile application Developer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;She introduced us to Detox, an open-source tool used for end-to-end integration testing. She gave us insights into integrating E2E testing seamlessly into a continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD) pipeline and spoke about strategies for efficient mocking and stubbing in various testing scenarios.&#xA;All in all, it was a refreshing presentation on an app&#39;s journey from development to deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;panel-discussion-on-cybersecurity&#34;&gt;Panel Discussion on Cybersecurity &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#panel-discussion-on-cybersecurity&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Panel Discussion on Cybersecurity was a highlight of the FOSS meetup, providing a platform for 4 experts to share valuable thoughts on their best practices for frontend Web Security.&#xA;Some of the crucial topics addressed during this session included strategies for enhancing the security of query parameters, techniques for purifying the Document Object Model (DOM) to prevent potential vulnerabilities, comprehensive insights into XSS attacks and mitigation strategies, the pivotal role of input validation in ensuring application security, strategies for simulating and securing API endpoints, insights into addressing DDoS attacks, and ensuring the security of data stored in S3 containers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/DbBjVWX.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The team that made it possible&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The FOSS meetup was a fun and valuable experience (with a lot of food) that deepened our understanding of frontend development and emphasized the critical importance of cybersecurity. Kudos to FOSS United Bangalore and GeekyAnts for this event!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HSP Manifesto 2023</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//manifesto/hspmanifesto2023.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//manifesto/hspmanifesto2023.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#table-of-contents&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#year-in-review&#34;&gt;Year in Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#whats-new&#34;&gt;What&#39;s New?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#-to-keep-the-spirit-of-building-alive-and-carry-on-the-tradition-of-knowledge-sharing-&#34;&gt;To keep the spirit of building alive and carry on the tradition of knowledge sharing.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#closing-note&#34;&gt;Closing Note&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The humble tradition of writing down a manifesto for Hackerspace ECC was started by our ex-core team lead, exactly a year ago. As Maya Angelou once said &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Traditions are not chains that bind us, but wings that lift us”&lt;/strong&gt;, it is only right to keep this practice alive that in turn, kept us going as we steadily grew in size, ambition, and impact. The manifesto is a declaration of our collective goals and aspirations for HSP. It helps us be more transparent, remember what we are working towards, and keeps us accountable, together as a club fostering community-powered development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;year-in-review&#34;&gt;Year in Review &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#year-in-review&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have had an exponential year; of learning and records that broke what was once considered successful. Having seminar halls brimming with students attending the most niche workshops we’ve held to culminating a diverse range of quality recruits, loaded with ideas and an unmatched skillset, and from publishing resourceful blogs to giving talks at reputed meetups, every branch that’s unfolded from the sapling, HSP once was, to now, firmly establishing its presence as a mighty Oak, deeply rooted in fostering the spirit of FOSS. The quality of initiatives and the quantity of club members who embody HSP’s vision is an achievement that we proudly celebrate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-new&#34;&gt;What&#39;s New? &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#whats-new&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The core team of 2023-2024 will be actively working towards strengthening this mighty Oak. Pushing boundaries, finding newer challenges to work on, exploring uncharted areas of innovation, and, yet remaining deep-rooted in HSP’s vision:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-to-keep-the-spirit-of-building-alive-and-carry-on-the-tradition-of-knowledge-sharing-&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;To keep the spirit of building alive and carry on the tradition of knowledge sharing.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#-to-keep-the-spirit-of-building-alive-and-carry-on-the-tradition-of-knowledge-sharing-&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Standing on the shoulders of giants, the new core is all set to amplify what we’ve been nurtured to do; lead by example. Tilde 2.0 was the first initiative that was born from the learning gaps of the older iteration, emphasizing the importance of reiteration and pivots. We built a haven for students during the summer, to actively upskill in their domains of interest and build projects with the help of our expert mentors who volunteered to teach what they love.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Without slowing down the pace, we have been ferviously working on ideas that would help amplify the technical temperament on campus and outside, too!&#xA;Things in Store include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshops&lt;/strong&gt; - HSP is known for its niche topics and we promise to deliver nothing less. We have a great bunch of proposals from the mentor team and we’ll be conducting 3-4 workshops this semester.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fireside Chats&lt;/strong&gt; - A biweekly meetup at the quadrangle to sit, chill and discuss what you&#39;re working on, bottlenecks in your domain of interest, or even think about project ideas you’d work on, during breaks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breakdown Series&lt;/strong&gt; - To inculcate the healthy practice of reading technical papers, we will be having group discussions where we simplify, understand, and question the scope/limitations of these research findings.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hex&lt;/strong&gt; - Hackerspace Exchange; a forum that curates knowledge in the form of courses, links, and projects.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These initiatives are not easy to pull off, but we’ve done hard things before and we shall do it again. Starting communities from scratch is a challenge on its own, but keeping one buzzing is another. Irrespective of how hard it may be, it&#39;s one of those adventures we look forward to embarking on with you all. We’ll learn, have fun nerding out and spread a seed or two of knowledge as we go.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-note&#34;&gt;Closing Note &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#closing-note&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve reached here, it means, you’ve been through the ride and I sincerely appreciate it. If you aren’t a member of HSP and would like to change that, then keep an eye out on our social handles for recruitments and if you are an already existing member, then we strongly look forward to seeing your active participation in bringing these initiatives to life. We need you to help knit this up with us, and give in your POVs, your ideas, and your invaluable contributions, irrespective of which domain you come from.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lastly, you would have also noticed that we’re now going by HSP. This is because we may have started off as Hackerspace ECC, but we’ve grown leaps and bounds in terms of ideologies and initiatives; thus crafting a need to carve out a new, refined, and separate identity for ourselves. Here’s to building; the community and your skillset! Onwards and Upwards!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Harini Anand&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Co-Head of HSP&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;9/8/2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//history.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//history.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;launchpad-2021&#34;&gt;LaunchPad 2021&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Marking HackerSpace ECC&#39;s inaugural event, LaunchPad 2021 unfolded as a dynamic three-stage ideathon, offering participants a diverse array of categories including&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI/ML&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Blockchain&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cloud Computing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;IoT&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Big Data and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Distributed Systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The event garnered robust support from esteemed sponsors, notably PESU Venture Labs, Balsamiq, and Wolfram Languages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spanning from &lt;strong&gt;October 24th to 28th, 2021&lt;/strong&gt;, this exceptional competition commenced with an engaging online preliminary round, proceeding to grand finale conducted offline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;homebrew-foss-by-hackerspace-pesuecchttpshomebrewhsp-ecxyz&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://homebrew.hsp-ec.xyz/&#34;&gt;Homebrew FOSS by HackerSpace PESUECC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was the idea behind Homebrew?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Homebrew is a gathering place for FOSS enthusiasts on campus. It was created with the idea to solve the absence of a major FOSS Community in PES. It serves as a hub where enthusiasts engage in conversations about their preferred open source technologies, share alternatives, and propose different software options. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the platform hosts the &amp;quot;Homebrew Expo&amp;quot; on a weekly basis, offering students a platform to showcase their projects, mirroring the spirit of the actual Homebrew community.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having been in existence for nearly a year, Homebrew has established itself as a valuable platform for sharing thoughts, ideas, and guides related to emerging technologies. Members of the community contribute their insights to assist and guide other individuals seeking information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are a few &lt;a href=&#34;https://sharp-wright-d62960.netlify.app/blog/&#34;&gt;blogs and guides&lt;/a&gt; written by some of the members of HackerSpace PESU-ECC.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our members have also had the amazing oppurtunity to speak at some of &lt;strong&gt;FOSS United Bangalore&#39;s&lt;/strong&gt; meetups&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/wIWHqub.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;systemctl-start-linuxhttpswwwhsp-ecxyzeventssystemctl-start-linux&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hsp-ec.xyz/events/systemctl-start-linux/&#34;&gt;systemctl start linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;systemctl start linux was a beginner-oriented, hands-on workshop conducted by Hackerspace PESUECC where the club members, many of whom use Linux as their primary operating system, exhibited their configurations and setups, and answered variety of questions from the participants!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Course of Events :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An Introduction to the Linux OS and bash commands to demonstrate its flexibility.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How is Linux beneficial from a FOSS Perspective.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hands-on session with bash, shell scripting and common command-line tools.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A brief Introduction to Vim- a free and open-source, screen-based text editor program.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;build-your-own-websitehttpswwwhsp-ecxyzeventsbyow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hsp-ec.xyz/events/byow/&#34;&gt;Build your Own Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the occasion of Engineer&#39;s day, HackerSpace PESU-ECC presented a beginner friendly interactive workshop on web development using Eleventy, a static site generator used by Google, CERN, and many others!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The workshop covered a wide range of topics including:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eleventy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;HTML&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CSS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Netlify&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Creating your very own website by the end of the workshop&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;golang-101httpswwwhsp-ecxyzeventsgolang22&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hsp-ec.xyz/events/golang22/&#34;&gt;Golang 101&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HackerSpace PESU-ECC also conducted a exciting beginner friendly workshop on GO!&#xA;Golang is a language whose development is supported by Google and is syntactically similar to C.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The workshop covered a wide variety of topics :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Basics of Golang&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Why Golang is the fastest growing language in terms of popularity&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The amazing concurrency features included in GoLang&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Why Go is the language of choice for building enterprise-grade backend services.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;botcamphttpswwwhsp-ecxyzeventsbotcamp&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hsp-ec.xyz/events/botcamp/&#34;&gt;BotCamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BotCamp was a beginner-oriented, hands-on Telegram bot building workshop from HackerSpace PESUECC! ✨&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The workshop guided the participants on learning the basics of bot development with Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The workshop helped participants build their first Telegram bot using BotFather. They participants then deployed the bot on the app and made the bot do a variety of tasks like mimic the chats, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The participants also got to have a quick Q&amp;amp;A session with the Mentor Team of HackerSpace to get the gist of how to push their bot development skills in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/B7GFUj4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;compile-03&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Compile-03&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Build your Own Compiler!&lt;/em&gt; was a workshop presented by HackerSpace PESU-ECC in March 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The workshop covered what compilers are and how they work with binary language.&#xA;Participants were also familiarized with the workflow for writing assembly programs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By the end of the workshop, with the guidance of our mentors participants were capable of building and testing their first, very own compiler&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main aim of the workshop was that the participants should be capable of making their own language and know what to look for to expand their knowledge of the topic if interested.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/MwsJLfN.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;uiux-product-design-workshop&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;UI/UX Product Design Workshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the span of 2 days, HackerSpace PESU-ECC presented a workshop where one could develop their technical and design know-how, starting with the elementary thought process behind ideation to improvising and testing their final design. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;The workshop was beginner friendly and required minimal setup with mentors present to guide the participants along all the steps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/pqFKP3J.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;tilde&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Tilde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summer 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the summer of 2023, Tilde was HackerSpace’s mentorship program, spanning across 6 weeks where interested participants will be expanding your knowledge in your various domains through a project-based approach!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tilde was planned as a fun geek-out jam that participants can have with their mentor and network with like minded peers, who will guide and help them get better at your chosen domain!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tilde offered mentorship and guidance in Web Development, Backend and Systems engineering, Computer Architecture and Game Development domains.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;hsp-meetup&#34;&gt;HSP Meetup&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summer 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apart from Tilde 2.0, HackerSpace PESU-ECC attended a couple of meetups held across Bangalore,Karnataka.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We attended a meetup on &lt;strong&gt;Disruptive Tech - WebAssembly Serverless Edition, hosted at Google.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;The speakers at the first talk were &lt;strong&gt;Matt Butcher and Radu Matei, CEO and CTO at Fermyon Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;, a pioneer in WebAssembly and development in cloud computing, giving us an overview on the usage of Serverless functions and WebAssembly.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The second speaker was &lt;strong&gt;Saiyam Pathak&lt;/strong&gt;, giving an overview on usage of WebAssembly on Kubernetes, and running applications in Kubernetes clusters.&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/Z3EvCTb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We also attended meet-ups organised by Rust India, where 4 of our members gave insightful talks!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/navin_shrinivas/&#34;&gt;Navin Shrinivas&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk on Patterns and Anti-patterns of ORMs, in Rust&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ayaan_8/&#34;&gt;Mohammed Ayaan&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk on Judson, a project cleaner he built using Rust&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/anirudhrowjee/&#34;&gt;Anirudh Rowjee&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk on Saaru, a static site generator he built using Rust&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/suhas-kudlur-viswanath-33aa971ba&#34;&gt;Suhas KV&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk on RISCulator, a RISC-V emulator written in Rust&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/tSC0Baf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;fireside-talks&#34;&gt;Fireside Talks&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fireside Talks is a new venture by HackerSpace PESU-ECC where the club in association with ACM PESU-ECC aims to hold weekly meetups to inculcate the practise of discussing technical concepts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Members of both clubs come together and discuss, give their opinions on a topic collectively selected by the clubs. The members are provided with a bundle of resources to gain insights of the topic in dicussion and are free to contribute as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Up and Running</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/git_up_and_running.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/git_up_and_running.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;! WIP post !&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post is originally at &lt;a href=&#34;https://rowjee.com/blog/git_up_and_running&#34;&gt;https://rowjee.com/blog/git_up_and_running&lt;/a&gt;. Read Below for more -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bot-Camp</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/BotCamp.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/BotCamp.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;section class=&#34;p-index_links_link&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/fxtiaRVgcib1qqqN7&#34; class=&#34;c-gradient-link&#34;&gt; 👉 Register Now! &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/botcamp/botcamp.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Curious about building your own Telegram bot but don&#39;t know where to start?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presenting BotCamp, the beginner-oriented, hands-on Telegram bot building workshop from HackerSpace PESUECC! ✨&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Join us as we guide you to learn the basics of bot development with Telegram.&#xA;Our mentors will be there to guide newcomers through the whole process - from building the bot to deploying it. It&#39;s super easy as well: all you need is a Telegram account and Python!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This workshop will be held on the 24th of January, 2023 from 3:45 to 5:30 PM at the Seminar Hall, PESU EC Campus.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ll talk about, and have you experience -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Building your first Telegram bot using BotFather.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Deploying the Telegram bot and using it on the App.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Variations in the of tasks(&lt;em&gt;mimic chats&lt;/em&gt; etc.) the bot can do.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A quick Q&amp;amp;A session with the Mentor team of HackerSpace to know how to push ahead your bot development skills.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t miss this chance to jumpstart your bot-building journey. Register now!!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the event &lt;a href=&#34;https://homebrew.hsp-ec.xyz/posts/botcamp-or-the-telegram-bot-workshop/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/fxtiaRVgcib1qqqN7&#34;&gt;Click here to register directly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Registrations close on 22nd Jan!&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We can&#39;t wait to see you there!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For any further questions contact: Anirudh Rowjee, +91 9980029716&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Golang 101</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/golang22.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/golang22.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;section class=&#34;p-index_links_link&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/ztVkaGFWnZd42qby8&#34; class=&#34;c-gradient-link&#34;&gt; 👉 Register Now! &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/ztVkaGFWnZd42qby8&#34;&gt;registration form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/golang22/golang22_poster.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are you going to GO???&#xA;Greetings from HackerSpace PESU ECC! ✨✨&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You guessed it right! We are back with an exciting workshop, this time on Golang, a language whose development is supported by Google and is syntactically similar to C.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Date: 7th October&#xA;Time: 3:30PM-5:30PM&#xA;Venue: Seminar hall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why learn Go?🤔&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;✅ Golang is the fastest growing language in terms of popularity&#xA;✅ Go is the language of choice for building enterprise-grade backend services, used by companies such as Google, Visa, Uber, Twitch, DropBox, and Soundcloud&#xA;✅ Google uses Go A LOT! So, in case you’re eyeing the jobs there…👀&#xA;✅ Amazing concurrency, It is just brilliant! Don’t take our word for it, see for yourselves and register😌&#xA;✅ Go is a great place to finally start learning coding&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Need more reasons?&#xA;Other than the fact that it&#39;s beginner friendly and has NO entry fee and you&#39;ll be provided with extensive mentor support.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this workshop, we&#39;ll be walking through the basics of Golang and its concurrency features. This will enable you to start writing your own programs by the end of this workshop!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is your chance to get a huge head-start over your peers and classmates 🤫&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Get, set, go GOLANG😆&#xA;Register here -&#xA;https://hsp-ec.xyz/events/golang22&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basic 11ty Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/11tutorial.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/11tutorial.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#table-of-contents&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#begin-the-project&#34;&gt;Begin the project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#add-eleventy-config&#34;&gt;Add Eleventy Config&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#run-the-develop-server&#34;&gt;Run the develop Server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#create-the-base-layout&#34;&gt;Create the base layout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;begin-the-project&#34;&gt;Begin the project &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#begin-the-project&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;install NPM&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;initialising&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm init -y&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install @11ty/eleventy&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;open package.json and update scripts section to&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;scripts&amp;quot;: {&#xA;    &amp;quot;start&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;npx @11ty/eleventy --serve&amp;quot;,&#xA;    &amp;quot;build&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;npx @11ty/eleventy&amp;quot;&#xA;  },&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This enables a start command to run 11ty with hot-reload, which is provided by Browsersync that comes bundled as part of 11ty&#39;s --serve directive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;add-eleventy-config&#34;&gt;Add Eleventy Config &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#add-eleventy-config&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create .eleventy.js at the root&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;add&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;module.exports = function (eleventyConfig) {&#xA;  return {&#xA;    dir: {&#xA;      input: &amp;quot;src&amp;quot;,&#xA;      output: &amp;quot;public&amp;quot;,&#xA;    },&#xA;  };&#xA;};&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first change here is setting the input directory to src - as in, the directory 11ty will watch for changes and use to build for production. Then, we change the output directory to public which means that&#39;s where our production-ready files for use by localhost and a hosting server will be published.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;run-the-develop-server&#34;&gt;Run the develop Server &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#run-the-develop-server&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;npm start&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;error message as no index file&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create index file&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. create src/&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b. create src/index.md&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-the-base-layout&#34;&gt;Create the base layout &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#create-the-base-layout&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;create _includes/base.njk inside src.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;use the double-curly format to access the title Frontmatter variable, like so: {-{ title }} and in order to allow rendering of any HTML tags from the page content, we also use the built-in filter called safe which is added after placing a pipe - | - character.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&#xA;    &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&#xA;    &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&#xA;    &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;{-{ title }}&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&#xA;    &amp;lt;header&amp;gt;{-{ title }}&amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;&#xA;    &amp;lt;main&amp;gt;{-{ content | safe }}&amp;lt;/main&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ignore Hyphens(-).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Manually refresh and let Browsersync do the rest.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prerequisite for the 11ty Workshop</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/prereqisite.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/prereqisite.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#table-of-contents&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#git&#34;&gt;GIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#volta&#34;&gt;Volta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#netlify&#34;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dependencies of the workshop are mentioned below&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;git&#34;&gt;GIT &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#git&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Git CLI installation see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/install-git&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setting your Git username for every repository on your computer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Set a Git username:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git config --global user.name &amp;quot;Mona Lisa&amp;quot;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Confirm that you have set the Git username correctly:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git config --global user.name&#xA;&amp;gt; Mona Lisa&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setting your email address for every repository on your computer&#xA;Open Terminal.&#xA;Set an email address in Git. You can use your GitHub-provided noreply email address or any email address.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git config --global user.email &amp;quot;email@example.com&amp;quot;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Confirm that you have set the email address correctly in Git:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git config --global user.email&#xA;&#xA;email@example.com&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Add the email address to your account on GitHub, so that your commits are attributed to you and appear in your contributions graph. For more information, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-user-account/adding-an-email-address-to-your-github-account&#34;&gt;Adding an email address to your GitHub account&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Authenticating with GitHub from Git:&#xA;see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/authentication/keeping-your-account-and-data-secure/creating-a-personal-access-token&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;volta&#34;&gt;Volta &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#volta&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repo uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://volta.sh/&#34;&gt;Volta&lt;/a&gt;. Get it, and it&#39;ll make your node life so much easier.&#xA;Run this command (for linux and mac user)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl https://get.volta.sh | bash&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For windows user follow instructions &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.volta.sh/guide/getting-started&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To install yarn&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;volta install yarn&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;netlify&#34;&gt;Netlify &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#netlify&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create an account on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.netlify.com/&#34;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build Your Own Website</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/byow.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/byow.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;section class=&#34;p-index_links_link&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/iPs8d3agf5i9H1LEA&#34; class=&#34;c-gradient-link&#34;&gt; 👉 Register Now! &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/byow/byow_poster_v5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do you want to build a website for yourself?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On occasion of Engineer’s day, HackerSpace PESU-ECC is back with an interactive workshop on web development using Eleventy, a static site generator used by Google, CERN, and many others! ✨&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Date: 16th September, 2022&#xA;Venue: Seminar Hall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why should you join it?&#xA;👉 Beginner friendly&#xA;👉 Covers a wide range of topics throughout the workshop, including Eleventy, HTML+CSS, and Netlify&#xA;👉 Create your own website by the end of it!&#xA;👉 Don’t miss the chance to flex the awesome technical skills you&#39;ll acquire!&#xA;👉 If you’re in the 1st sem, gives a headstart on web development.&#xA;👉 No entry fee!&#xA;👉 Mentors will be present in case of any difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://saksham-11ty.netlify.app/posts/2022/prereqisite/&#34;&gt;Click here for the pre-requisities!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is it for you?&#xA;Ofcourse! Students from all years are welcome to join in and learn more, and make their own website!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t forget to register! &lt;a href=&#34;https://tiy1l0l7c8l.typeform.com/to/ftfPjQbO&#34;&gt;Click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For any further questions contact: Anirudh Rowjee, +91 9980029716&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 2022 Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//manifesto/manifesto-2022.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//manifesto/manifesto-2022.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#table-of-contents&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#hackerspace-manifesto-2022&#34;&gt;Hackerspace manifesto 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#tilde&#34;&gt;Tilde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#homebrew&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#closing-note&#34;&gt;Closing Note&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;hackerspace-manifesto-2022&#34;&gt;Hackerspace manifesto 2022 &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#hackerspace-manifesto-2022&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hi there! I&#39;m Anirudh. I&#39;m the core team lead of Hackerspace PESUECC.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s said that writing is far more preferable compared to all other forms of expression, as good writing requires clear thinking. It&#39;s in this spirit that this blog post is ending up here, on the Hackerspace Website, and not on the usual channels of communication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I see this post having two main reasons to exist - firstly, to highlight how we&#39;ve grown not just as a student-run development club but also as a community. Secondly, and perhaps, most importantly, It&#39;s an attempt to establish the shared vision that I desparately hope will drive the further growth and development of this community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Hackerspace PESUECC started off as a whatsapp group back in April of 2021, the vision was a singular one - Establish HackerSpace as a club that functions at the same level in both campuses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, When I look at where we are today - having gone from a whatsapp group of five people and nothing else, to a thriving community of thirty-six student developers, designers, marketers, and operators, who are, and have been, the backbone of our three events, multiple projects, and our open-source community - I can&#39;t help but feel a deep sense of pride.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have come far, and there is, without a doubt, much to be appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At this juncture, I&#39;m reminded of Robert Frost&#39;s &amp;quot;Stopping by Woods on a Snowy Evening&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Poem so mentioned, Frost undertakes a wintertime journey through a lush, beautiful countryside, and happens to encounter some woody, forest-like land. Snow cascading down around him, he notices the inherent beauty in the silence, and stops to soak in this oasis in time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His horse, confused, makes a sound that snaps Frost out of his reverie. He realizes he must move on; for while the beautiful woods may well be a worthwhile halt, it isn&#39;t his destination. Frost puts it best -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The woods are lovely, dark and deep.&#xA;But I have promises to keep,&#xA;And miles to go before I sleep,&#xA;And miles to go before I sleep.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This leads to the question we, as members of HackerSpace PESUECC, need to ask ourselves - Is this really our destination?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throughout my time as the core team lead, I&#39;ve had the wonderful privilege of being a part of communities such as PES Open Source (now UniFOSS) and FOSS United.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In these communities, I understood that these two principles lie at the core of every functioning community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There exists a cause that brings like-minded folks together, and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There exists a framework for them to communicate, discuss, and collaborate, to work towards that cause.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, there&#39;s a dire need for every student-run community to aggressively focus on two principal tenets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Firstly, We must ensure that we keep the spirit of building alive. It&#39;s what has driven change and innovation since time immemorial, and it&#39;s critical to not only encourage, but in fact, celebrate the act of creation and invention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Irrespective of which hat you choose to wear - be it that of an engineer, a designer, an operator, a marketer, or a mentor, The act of building and creating in a tight feedback loop is foundational to the progress of one&#39;s skill and learning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Secondly, We must ensure that the spirit of Free and Open-Source Software (FOSS) isn&#39;t just maintained, but rather, is actively evangelized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOSS Runs the world, and this isn&#39;t an exaggeration by any means. These programs and libraries are the reason that Computers, Computer Science and Software Engineering is inexpensive and accessible to common people like you and me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As students, the largest beneficiaries of the FOSS Ecosystem, it&#39;s our responsibility to ensure that we carry on the tradition of free and open sharing of knowledge and software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the core of both these principles lie two extremely important factors - Community, and Knowledge Sharing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Builders and Creators cannot be the sole judges of their work - A feedback mechanism is necessary to help them become better. Knowledge must be shared for those listening to understand what&#39;s happening, and those building to know what they can do better.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, FOSS, by its nature, depends on community. Knowledge-sharing is built into the concept, for one can only learn more when their work is used in different ways by the community that exists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keeping these concepts, ideas, and principles in mind, I intend to ensure that HackerSpace PESUECC establishes a legacy of maintaining and growing the student FOSS Community, and of providing builders and creators a space to build and have their work bettered by feedback.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We intend to launch two major initiatives this year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tilde&#34;&gt;Tilde &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#tilde&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To ensure that builders and creators have a like-minded community of other builders and creators to help them become better, we intend to launch Tilde, a project development team initiative.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Students can volunteer to start projects or take over existing projects, working on them in two-week cycles in groups of four or five, driving them toward completion. We won&#39;t impose any limit on what the projects are, so long as there&#39;s a learning outcome from building it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Teams meet at the end of the two weeks to discuss progress, take feedback, and if necessary, re-evaluate the direction chosen. Builders and Creators who volunteer will be provided with a profile page to show off their work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;homebrew&#34;&gt;Homebrew &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#homebrew&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To carry on the tradition of Free and Open-Source Software communities, Homebrew is the FOSS wing of HackerSpace PESUECC. Homebrew will conduct regular talks and workshops to spread the message of FOSS, share knowledge about new tools, and at times, explore new projects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Homebrew will also meet once a week to show off and discuss projects that members of the community have been working that use FOSS Technologies. These meetings will be open, and anyone can attend - even those outside the community. These meetings can also be used to discuss new and interesting FOSS projects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With this, we intend to build a strong open-source community here, and carry on the legacy of those communities that came before us.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-note&#34;&gt;Closing Note &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#closing-note&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I believe the year ahead can be one of immense challenges - starting communities from scratch is no joke, and it&#39;s foolish to believe it&#39;ll be easy - but we&#39;re doing it because of the long-term gains, and not the short-term ones.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re someone who isn&#39;t a part of HackerSpace PESUECC, but you resonate with the goals and purposes of this message, please reach out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I look forward to seeing all of you joining us this year. Thank you for taking the time to read this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anirudh Rowjee&#xA;Core Team Lead, HackerSpace PESUECC&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Monday 08 August 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>systemctl start linux</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/systemctl-start-linux.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//events/systemctl-start-linux.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/systemctl-start-linux/post-preview.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why do those who use Linux swear by it so much?&#xA;What&#39;s so special about Linux that enables it to power most of the world&#39;s servers?&#xA;What does infinite customizability really mean?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;systemctl start linux&lt;/code&gt; is a beginner-oriented, hands-on workshop by Hackerspace PESUECC that aims to answer these questions for you. Join us, as we guide you on your Linux journey.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This workshop will be held on the 18th of April, 2022 from 4:00 to 6:00 PM at the Seminar Hall, PESU EC Campus.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;section class=&#34;p-index_links_link&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/PFmC8MZAB6uMArUW9&#34; class=&#34;c-gradient-link&#34;&gt;  Register Now! &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll talk about, and have you experience -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An Introduction to the Linux OS and bash commands to demonstrate its flexibility&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How is Linux beneficial from a FOSS Perspective?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hands-on session with bash, shell scripting and common command-line tools&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A brief Introduction to Vim&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, the Mentor Team at Hackerspace PESUECC, many of whom use Linux as their primary operating system, will exhibit their configurations and setups, and are available to answer your questions!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the event here - &lt;a href=&#34;https://hsp-ec.xyz/events/systemctl-start-linux&#34;&gt;https://hsp-ec.xyz/events/systemctl-start-linux&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;Register here directly - &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/PFmC8MZAB6uMArUW9&#34;&gt;https://forms.gle/PFmC8MZAB6uMArUW9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See you there!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//about.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//about.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>home</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//members.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//members.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;members&#34;&gt;Members&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mentor&#34;&gt;Mentor&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;operations&#34;&gt;Operations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;marketing&#34;&gt;Marketing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>home</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//index.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;/static/images/home.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;image of us&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;hsppesuecc&#34;&gt;HSPPESUECC&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p style=&#34;font-size: 1.6rem; font-weight: 350; font-family: AzeretMono;&#34;&gt; Hackerspace PESUECC is a Student-Powered Developer Community located at PES University, Electronic City Campus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The club was started in 2021, with a founding team of five people. Presently, the club has more than 36 Staff, and remains an open, student-run and student-directed community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;featured&#34;&gt;Featured&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//socials.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//socials.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instagram:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gallery</title>
      <link>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//gallery.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>HSP</author>
      <guid>https://anirudhsudhir.github.io/test-hsp//gallery.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gallery goes here&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
